Ismael Penacho

CAPABILITIES

Self-taught, Self-starter, soft skills, proactive, team player, leadership and open to learn.

SKILLS

- Offensive WiFi cybersecurity, OSINT, networks and protocols
- Vulnerability scans Exploitation
- Enumeration and Gathering
- Nmap, Burp Suite, Airodump-ng, Kali Linux tools
- SysAdmin
- C, C++, Java, Python, Go, Bash, SQL
- EN: Average level
- ES: Native level

CERTIFICATIONS

- eIPT
- eWPT (coming soon)

CONTACT INFORMATION

@ p3n4x0@protonmail.com

in LinkedIn

G GitHub

■ WebSite

ABOUT ME

Computer Scienciest with experience in cybersecurity. Currently, I work on secure environments by achieving best of class policy coverage and automation for 360° security across workloads, hosts, container orchestration, and cloud. Passionate about pentesting and solving security challenges, in my free time, I enjoy solving machines in HackTheBox and TryHackMe to further develop my skills in computer security and continue to grow professionally in the field of cybersecurity.

EXPERIENCE

SECURITY ANALYST at Sysdig.

Jan 2024-Currently

- ♦ Advanced programming in Go and OPA Rego.
- Oloud Security (AWS, GCP and Azure), Hosts and Kubernetes.
- ♦ IaC Security (TF, CFT).
- ♦ Knowledge of different security policies and standards.

RED TEAM LEAD at DigitalHM.

Sept 2023-Jan 2024

Same technical tasks plus leadership and coordination.

RED TEAM OPERATOR at DigitalHM.

Jun 2023-Sept 2023

- ♦ Information Gathering, OSINT.
- ⋄ Vulnerability Assessment.
- Phishing y Malware campaigns.
- Automation of tasks by scripts.

CYBER SECURITY ENGINEER at NoLogin.

Jul 2022-Sept 2022

- Server and service monitoring of onpremise/cloud environments.
- Scripting maintenance and functionality development.

EDUCATION

MASTER IN CYBERSECURITY. IMF Smart Education.

2023-2024

- Thesis: Pentesting of a Content Management System
- ♦ Average Grade: 8.7/10
- CyberIntelligence.
- ♦ Ethical Hacking.
- Secure Development.
- ♦ SIEM.
- Reverse Engineering.
- Smartphone Hacking.
- ⋄ Forensic Analisys.

COMPUTER SCIENCE. University of Zaragoza.

2019-2023

- ♦ Thesis: WiFiGhost, Offensive WiFi audit tool.
- ♦ Average Grade: 7.0/10

VOLUNTEER OR LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

2019 Google Hackathon, 2020 Google Hackathon, 2021 Google Hackathon & 2024 Sysdig Hackathon.

Member of the School of CTFs organized by the RME-DisCo research group of the University of Zaragoza. Active participant in CTFs since 2022.

Machine completion on HackTheBox and TryHackMe.